.svg)

.svg)

##### Log in or sign up

##### or

By continuing, you agree to our [terms](http:?hsLang=en-nz) of use and [privacy policy](http:?hsLang=en-nz)

    **

**Updated April 2024**  

realestate.co.nz 's policy on keeping your privacy protected.

We take our responsibility to protect your personal information very seriously. “Personal information” means information about an identifiable individual. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, disclose, and protect the personal information you provide to us when you use our website, mobile apps, or products and services (services).

**Protecting you and your privacy**

We are committed to collecting, using, and protecting your personal information in accordance with New Zealand’s Privacy Act ( Privacy Act 2020 ) and any replacement legislation. You can find out more about the Act on the Privacy Commissioner’s [website](https://www.privacy.org.nz/privacy-act-2020/privacy-principles/ "https://www.privacy.org.nz/").

**What information we collect and how we do it**

In most cases, we collect your personal information directly from you.

1. Information you provide to us.

Account information: As a visitor to our website, you have the option to create an account with us. To create an account, you need to provide us with some personal information, such as your name, password, and email address. All of this information is necessary for us to operate your account and provide you with our services. If you do not provide this information, we cannot register you with an account, we will not be able to send communications/information to you, and you may not be able to use some of our services. We also collect your IP address when you create an account with us.

Information saved to your account: If you have created an account, and you are logged in, information about your use of our website and services will be linked to your account. This will include any mortgage calculator information you provide, all information you choose to save to your account (such as your searches, properties, locations, and notes) as well as your search criteria and any pages/properties you view that you do not save.

When using our website or services: If you choose to use some of our services or receive communications from us, you may be asked to provide us with personal information (for e.g.: your name and email address).

Your communications with us: When you communicate with us (such as phone calls, emails or via social media), we may collect information about that communication. This may include personal information and any other information you provide during the communication.

Other information: When you provide us with other information directly (via email or any other formats) for example if you complete a form, provide us feedback, participate in surveys and promotions or when asked to help with research and development of new products and features, if you decide to give us a hand.

2\. Information we collect when you access our website and app, and use our services.

Information we automatically collect: When you use our website and services, we collect information about your use. This includes:

* Your use of our website, including your browsing patterns, search criteria, pages and properties you view, and your use of any features and services available on our website.
* Your general location.
* Your IP address, hardware and software information, device information, and your geo-demographic information.

How we collect this information: We collect this information via:

* The use of cookies and other similar technologies. A cookie is a small file which is stored in your web browser. This collection may occur across different devices. If you use our website before you create an account, information collected by cookies regarding your prior usage may be assigned to your account. You can disable cookies through our Cookie Preferences (see Opt-Out Information below). Currently, we use third parties such as Google Analytics, HubSpot, Braze, HotJar, Facebook, Google AdWords, and Lotame to do this for us.
* A guest token which is applied when you use our website.

Third party cookies: We also allow third parties to use cookies (and other similar technologies) on our website to collect information about your behaviour while using our website and services. This is for advertising and remarketing purposes. Currently these third parties include Google Analytics, Lotame DMP, HubSpot, Facebook, Google Ad Exchange, Google Ad Manager, Magnite (Formerly Rubicon), Index exchange, and Campaign Track. You can disable cookies through our Cookie Preferences, and you can opt out of targeted advertising (see Opt-Out Information below).

Our content may feature Nielsen’s proprietary measurement software, which contributes to market research, like Digital Content Ratings. To learn more about the information that Nielsen software may collect and your choices with regard to it, please see the Nielsen Digital Measurement Privacy Policy at [Digital measurement privacy statement](http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy.)

3\. Information we collect from third parties and public sources.

We may also collect information from third parties. The type of information we may collect is:

Information from public sources: We may obtain information about the organisation you work for from your email address (currently via Braze). We also collect property information from REINZ (who collect the information from public sources such as past sales history and sales details, zoning, CVs, etc.) however we do not link this information to you.

Analytics information: We may collect analytics information (such as information about your device, applications, operating system, IP address and geo-demographic information) from third parties (such as Google Analytics).

realestate.co.nz allows users to login via Facebook. If you would like to delete your Facebook login data, you can do so, by following these steps:

1. Go to your Facebook Account's Settings & Privacy.
2. Click on Settings.
3. Look for Apps and Websites, where you'll see all the apps and websites connected to your Facebook account.
4. Search for and select the [realestate.co.nz](http://realestate.co.nz/) app.
5. Scroll down and click Remove. 

**What do we do with this information?**

We use your personal information to provide our services to you and so we can make your user experience on our website the best in market. We may use your information to:

Provide services to you: Provide you with our services including personalising your experience on our website when using our website and services.

Communicate with you: Contact you with information relating to our website and services, including promotional material or advertising about our services and the products and services of third parties.

Analyse, improve and develop new services: Analyse the performance and effectiveness of our website, services, advertising, and marketing, to improve our website and services and to develop new services. We may also use your information to investigate any action that may threaten network security or integrity.

Machine learning and Generative AI: Analyse various types of data to provide personalised services, property recommendations, and market insights.

Market, advertise, and promote services to you: Market, advertise, and promote our services to you and the products and services of third parties. This includes displaying to you customised or targeted promotional material or advertising (based on your past activity on our website and other websites) and remarketing our services to you (see below for further information on remarketing). See Opt-Out Information below for how to opt-out of these features.

Manage your enquiries/complaints: Deal with your requests, enquiries, or complaints and other customer care related activities.

Operate our business: carry out activities connected with the running of our business (e.g., personnel training, quality control, dispute resolution, and network monitoring).

Law enforcement/government assistance: Render assistance to law enforcement, governmental and regulatory agencies or otherwise for legal compliance or law enforcement purposes.

**Who we share your information with**

Third party service providers: So that we can provide our services and improve our services, we may need to disclose some of your personal information to our third-party service providers. Any sharing of personal information with our service providers will only occur if it is necessary so the service provider can provide their services to us. It will also be in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Currently we share personal information with the following service providers:

* Osano Technologies – Managing data and user’s privacy
* Amazon Web Services – Data Storage (such as your account information)
* Google Analytics – For Reporting and Machine Learning (such as Internal metrics reporting)
* Lotame – Website browsing information (such as cookie browsing behavioural patterns).
* Salesforce – CRM (customer relationship management).
* Campaign Track – Website browsing information (such as cookie browsing behavioural patterns).
* HotJar - Website browsing information (such as clickthrough).
* Braze – Customer engagement platform to communicate with our users via email or push notifications (in app) (such as newsletters and marketing communications).
* Yahoo Ad tech – Advertisement technology platform that collects information (such as location, screen size, time of day) to serve personalized/relevant ads.
* Magnite (Formerly Rubicon) - Advertisement technology platform that collects information (such as location, screen size, time of day) to serve personalized/relevant ads.
* Index Exchange - Advertisement technology platform that collects information (such as location, screen size, time of day) to serve personalized/relevant ads.

Law enforcement: We may disclose your personal information to law enforcement, governmental or regulatory agencies for legal compliance or law enforcement purposes.

Third parties: We share the information collected from cookies and your use of our website and services with third parties who use it for marketing or advertising purposes and to display customised or targeted promotional, marketing or advertising material on our website and on other websites that you visit. Currently, third parties include Google Analytics, Lotame DMP, HubSpot Google Display Network, Facebook, Campaign Track and our selected business partners (currently mortgage calculator) who may use the cookie information for their own purposes as well as their client’s purposes. The Privacy Policies of the third parties apply to the personal information we share with them.

Remarketing: Remarketing is where your browsing history on a website is then used to show you advertising related to your history once you have left that website. For example, a property listing you have viewed on our website may be remarketed to you while you are accessing another website. We supply cookie information (from your browser) about your browsing history on our website to the following remarketing providers: Campaign Track, Facebook, Google Display Network and Google DoubleClick Bid Manager. If you wish to opt-out of remarketing, see Opt-Out Information below.

Our content may feature Nielsen’s proprietary measurement software, which will allow you to contribute to market research, like Digital Content Ratings. To learn more about the information that Nielsen software may collect and your choices regarding it, please see the Nielsen Digital Measurement Privacy Policy at [Digital measurement privacy statement](http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy)

Other information: We may provide anonymised and aggregated user information to our service providers, business partners or other third parties.

**Opt-out information**

How to disable cookies, opt-out of analytics, targeted advertising, and remarketing

Most web browsers allow you to control cookies in your browser settings by setting your browsers to accept or reject all or certain cookies. Please note if you choose to disable all cookies this may affect your ability to use some of the features on our site. The following provides information on how you can manage cookies in your web browser: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "http://www.allaboutcookies.org/") and [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "http://www.aboutcookies.org/") .

You can opt-out of non-essential cookies on our platform [https://www.realestate.co.nz/](https://www.realestate.co.nz/ "https://www.realestate.co.nz/") and navigating to the footer of the page and click on ‘cookie preferences’.

Our ‘Storage Preference’ modal will open on the screen and you can see the three main categories of cookies you can opt in or out of. This is also where you can see the exact cookies we store if you decide to opt in for cookie tracking.

**Marketing** - These items are used to deliver advertising that is more relevant to you and your interests. They may also be used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement and measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. Advertising networks usually place them with the website operator’s permission.

**Personalisation** - These items allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language, or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. For example, a website may provide you with local weather reports or traffic news by storing data about your current location.

**Analytics** - These items help the website operator understand how its website performs, how visitors interact with the site, and whether there may be technical issues. This storage type usually doesn’t collect information that identifies a visitor.

We may make advertising space available on our website through certain advertising platforms or exchanges, such as DoubleClick Ad Exchange, Magnite (Formerly Rubicon), Index Exchange, you can manage what you see due to DoubleClick cookies through Google’s Ad Settings. You may also be able to opt out of our advertising by visiting the websites of the [Network Advertising Initiative](https://thenai.org/ "https://thenai.org/") or Digital Advertising Alliance. If you opt out of customised advertising, the advertising you see may be less relevant to you.

You can opt out of remarketing, here [opt out of the DoubleClick cookie](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin "https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin") and [double-check your Facebook Adverts settings](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads "https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads") .

\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_

**Updated September 2023**

**Privacy Policy – Listing Content**

realestate.co.nz 's policy on keeping your privacy protected.

We take our responsibility to protect your personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, disclose and protect the personal information in listing content that is provided to us by licensed real estate agents and salespeople and other third parties for listing on our website and for providing our products and services. “Personal information” means information about an identifiable individual. 

**Protecting you and your privacy**

We are committed to collecting, using, and protecting personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act 2020 (Act) and any replacement legislation. You can find out more about the Act on the Privacy Commissioner’s [website](https://www.privacy.org.nz/). 

**What information we collect and how we do it** 

We collect listing content, such as:

* a description of the listing and type of listing.
* photos of the property/business and a map showing where the listing is located.
* a “for sale” listing: how the property/business is to be sold (for example, by negotiation, tender, auction).
* a “for sale/for rent property” listing: schools in the area.
* a “for sale property” listing: Capital Value of the property, property history.
* and other information that may be of relevance to the listing.

We collect this information from third parties, such as licensed real estate agents and salespeople, education.govt.nz, and local councils, Google maps and from other publicly available registers and databases.

**What do we do with this information?** 

We use listing content to:

* Make publicly available on our website.
* Make available to trusted third parties who use our API and may appear on other websites or applications.
* Provide our products and services.
* Enrich the data bases of trusted third parties to be used by them in providing and promoting products and services.
* Analyse, improve and develop new products and services.
* Analytical, statistical and research purposes.
* Operate our business and for internal back up and reporting.
* Law enforcement/government assistance: Render assistance to law enforcement, governmental and regulatory agencies or otherwise for legal compliance or law enforcement purposes.

**Who we share your information with** 

We share listing content for the purposes set out above, and this includes with:

* Third party service providers.
* Trusted third parties; and
* law enforcement, governmental or regulatory agencies for legal compliance or law enforcement purposes.

**Who holds your information?** 

We hold the listing content. Some of the listing content will be stored and/or processed by third parties on our behalf, such as Google Analytics, Hubspot, Braze, SendGrid, Lotame (DMP) and Amazon Web Services.

**How we protect your information** 

We take all the reasonable steps we can to ensure that any personal information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up-to-date, and stored in a secure environment protected from loss or unauthorised access, use, modification, or disclosure.

**How long we keep your information**

We keep listing content for as long as is reasonably required for us to use it in accordance with the purposes set out above. 

**Your right to access and correct your personal information**

You can request access to and correction of any personal information that we hold about you.

If you would like to contact us regarding your personal information, please fill out the form [here](https://www.realestate.co.nz/data-request)

You may also contact the Privacy Commissioner by following the process described on the Privacy Commissioner’s [website](https://www.privacy.org.nz/your-rights/making-a-complaint/). 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

If we need to, we may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any change we make applies from the date the updated Privacy Policy is posted on our website

##### Locations

##### Explore

##### About realestate.co.nz

* [Cookie Preferences](javascript:void(0);)

##### Our related sites

##### My property

##### Locations

##### Explore

##### About realestate.co.nz

* [Cookie Preferences](javascript:void(0);)

##### Our related sites

##### My property

* ###### Download our app

###### Copyright realestate.co.nz 2022

###### Download our app

###### Copyright realestate.co.nz 2022
